{
    "id": "3c7d716ad5bf4903833b5c5b856352a8",
    "title": "Phrasal Verbs Exercise",
    "questions": [
        {
            "question": "The High Court ………………………. the decree of the lower court.",
            "description": "To set a law aside is to annul it.",
            "answers": [
                "set out",
                "set off",
                "set aside"
            ],
            "correct": 2
        },
        {
            "question": "I was determined to ………………………",
            "description": "To speak out is to express your opinion freely.",
            "answers": [
                "speak out",
                "speak for",
                "speak of"
            ],
            "correct": 0
        },
        {
            "question": "He always …………………………… the weak and the oppressed.",
            "description": "To stand up for something / somebody is to champion the cause of it / them.",
            "answers": [
                "stood out for",
                "stood up for",
                "stood up"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "The sofa …………………………. too much room.",
            "description": "Takes up means occupies.",
            "answers": [
                "takes in",
                "takes up",
                "takes out"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "The cistern is ……………………………",
            "description": "Running over means overflowing.",
            "answers": [
                "running up",
                "running out",
                "running over"
            ],
            "correct": 2
        },
        {
            "question": "I can no longer ……………………….. your insolence.",
            "description": "To put up with something is to tolerate it.",
            "answers": [
                "put up with",
                "put out with",
                "put off with"
            ],
            "correct": 0
        },
        {
            "question": "He was …………………………. when I refused his offer.",
            "description": "Be put out can mean annoyed or vexed.",
            "answers": [
                "put out",
                "put up",
                "put over"
            ],
            "correct": 0
        },
        {
            "question": "It didn’t take him too long to ………………………. his fortune.",
            "description": "To run through fortune is to squander it away.",
            "answers": [
                "run up",
                "run through",
                "run over"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "In his speech on tolerance, he ………………………… his views at length.",
            "description": "To set forth your views is to explain it clearly.",
            "answers": [
                "set out",
                "set forth",
                "set up"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "I could easily ………………………….. his trick.",
            "description": "To see through something is to detect the true nature of. ",
            "answers": [
                "see over",
                "see through",
                "see off"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "Monsoon in India ………………………….. about June.",
            "description": "When a season sets in, it begins.",
            "answers": [
                "sets out",
                "sets in",
                "sets for"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "We shall be formidable if we ………………………… one another.",
            "description": "To stand by somebody is to support them.",
            "answers": [
                "stand with",
                "stand by",
                "stand out"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        }
    ]
}